

+92 336 794661890tricks90@gmail.comSaddar, Lahore, Pakistan

# **Summary**

Hi, I am a passionate UI/UX Designer & Full-Stack Developer from Lahore, Pakistan. I want to make things that make a difference. I am responsible for creating and implementing an array of Web-based products using Laravel, PHP, MySQL, JavaScript, React JS, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap, and More. I have 3+ Years of Strong Experience in the field of Website Development, and also have some experience & expertise In Graphics Designing and also experience in teaching Web Development and various Computer Science Subjects.

If you looking for a professional / Qualified full-stack Website Developer, junior Graphics Designer then Congrats! You are at the right place. I think that I'm absolutely fine for you which can do your job perfectly. If You Want to Learn More AboutMe, Feel Free to Visit My Personal Portfolio Website: https://abubakarwebdev.github.io/

### **Skills**

- Adobe XD
- CSS 3
- JavaScript
- Laravel
- MYSQL
- PHP
- Search Engine Optimization
- Type Script

- Bootstrap 5
- HTML 5
- jQuery
- LINUX & UBUNTU
- NPM
- React JS
- SQL
- Visual Studio Code

- C / C++
- Illustrator
- JSON
- Microsoft SQL Server
- Photoshop
- SaaS
- Tailwind CSS
- WordPress

# **Experience**

### **FULL STACK REACT, LARAVEL & WORDPRESS DEVELOPER**

Ghar47.com, Lahore, Pakistan

Jul 2020 - Nov 2021

- Acted as lead developer managing a team of two for implementing great functionalities.
- Integrated various third-party APIs using REST/JSON
  Also, worked parallelly on different projects like Advertisement posting system, Property Management System,
  Blogging management system, and much more.

#### **FULL STACK PHP, WORDPRESS DEVELOPER**

WeTeachQuran.com & OneStepSol.com, Lahore, Pakistan

Jan 2020 - Jun 2020

Developed the website of WeTeachQuran with Nice Looking Design and Extra-Ordinary Functionality. Launched an internal learning management system utilizing primarily PHP and MySQL to introduce a more scalable and reliable solution that gives 100% best performance and functionality.

### **Teaching Web Development & Computer Science Subjects**

Home Based Tuition as Well as Online Teaching, Lahore, Pakistan

Dec 2018 - Jan 2020

- I taught web Development, Programming Fundamentals, Object-Oriented Programming to My Students.Great
- Teaching Experience with Different Platforms and Students.

#### FREELANCE FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

Freelancing on Fiverr & Project Based Working from Different Resources, Lahore, Pakistan

Feb 2018 - Dec 2018

- Design, Develop & Deliver A Nice-Looking Ecommerce Website According to
- Specifications.Collaborate with international as well as local clients with great working experience

## **Education**

### **University of Engineering & Technology Lahore (UET)**

BSc 2023

Computer Science

## **Federal Government Degree Collage, Lahore Cantt**

Intermediate/A-Level 2019

F. Sc Pre Engineering

#### Federal Government High School No.2, Lahore Cantt

Matriculation/O-Level 2017

**Biology** 

# Projects

## 30+ CREATED WEBSITES, 25+ WEB APPLICATIONS, 10+ WEBSITES USING CMS

https://github.com/AbubakarWebDev?tab=repositories

I created Professional JavaScript Web Applications with Nice Looking User Interface and a Memorable User Experience. I create Many Bootstrap & jQuery website Templates. I Also Create Many PHP Web Applications, PHP CMS, and Much More. All that stuff is hosted on my GitHub Account. If You want to check all these projects check the link given below.

I focus on building clean and minimalistic user interfaces. I learn much more tips and Techniques from my experience with my effortful work. Please give a chance me for doing professional work for you. I am Looking forward to hearing from you, Your Promptness In this Regard was highly appreciated.

#### Links:

GitHub Account Link: https://github.com/AbubakarWebDev

My Personal Portfolio Website: https://abubakarwebdev.github.io/

All Created Websites Link: https://abubakarwebdev.github.io/websites/

All Created Web Applications Link: https://abubakarwebdev.github.io/webapplications/

All Created PHP MYSQL Projects Link: https://github.com/AbubakarWebDev/php-mysql-projects

# **A** Languages

Punjabi	Urdu	English
Beginner	Expert	Intermediate